Ihor Hontarenko

+380 66 102 10 41 igor.gontarenko@gmail.com Kyiv, Ukraine

Summary

I'm specializing in web development with 6+ years of professional experience with a full understanding of the web development process, including design, development, and deployment. I have high-level operability, can work independently, and use resources efficiently.



Objective

UI Engineer

Experience

Company «Perfectial», Kyiv, Ukraine UI Engineer

Feb 2020 - Present

- styling React elements with JSX on TypeScript by using SCSS
- creating animations by using CSS3, SVG, GSAP library
- setup and development WordPress and Shopify projects
- building a UI structure of the projects and modularize components with React
- working according to the Agile methodology by using Scrum way
- reviewing teammates' pull requests on the Bitbucket
- support existing projects

Company «Clock Creative Lab», Kyiv, Ukraine Front-End Web Developer

Mar 2017 - Jan 2020

- markup HTML5 layouts from scratch on SCSS by using BEM methodology
- creating animations by using JavaScript, jQuery, CSS3, SVG
- code verification and merging pull requests on the GitHub
- distribution of technical tasks between developers
- building Progressive Web Apps
- support existing projects

Company «Mediaset», Kyiv, Ukraine Full Stack Web Developer Nov 2015 - Mar 2017

- markup HTML layouts from scratch on Less
- creating animations by using JavaScript, jQuery
- setup and development WordPress and Django projects
- find and use new web technologies to solve problems
- support existing projects

Education

National Technical University of Ukraine «Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute» 2015 – 2017

Faculty of Informatics and Computer Technology

Master's degree

Computer Science

National Technical University of Ukraine «Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute» 2011 – 2015

Faculty of Informatics and Computer Technology

Bachelor's degree

Computer Science

Skills

- proficient in JavaScript, jQuery, JSX, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, SVG, BEM methodology, Progressive Web Apps
- good knowledge of React, Redux, TypeScript, AJAX, JSON, REST API, GSAP library, Three.js
- working with HUGO, Bootstrap, Materialize, Compass, and some other frameworks
- working knowledge of MySQL database and some CMS (WordPress, Shopify, Django)
- using Gulp, Webpack toolkits, GitHub, and Bitbucket repository
- familiar with version control systems and development team workflow (Agile, Scrum, Kanban)
- proficient understanding of concept development, layout composition, site functionality, navigation, and understanding of building responsive, valid, cross-browser friendly applications
- great experience in implementing UI/UX design, ability to translate it from Adobe XD, Figma, Sketch,
 Photoshop, etc. into clean, accurate code by using pixel perfect, sprites, linters

Additional Information

- developed the official websites <u>Eurovision Song Contest Kyiv</u>, <u>Mercedes-Benz Ukraine</u>, <u>Audi Ukraine</u> and <u>KIA Motors Ukraine</u> Progressive Web App for Car Service & Repair
- obtained 3D Programming with JavaScript and Three.js 3D Library certificate
- obtained certificates of achievement: HTML, CSS and JavaScript Essential
- obtained Luxoft Agile Practice certificate on the Scrum Basics Workshop
- took part in the UA Web Challenge

Languages

English - B2

References

gontarenko.pp.ua t.me/mysecondspace github.com/mysecondspace linkedin.com/in/gontarenko facebook.com/mysecondspace